Inventory of the Violet L. Barnett Diaries 1920-1972
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Violet L. Barnett Diaries 1920-1972 1931-1972
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2009.504
1.00
35 volumes.
Diaries of Violet Laughead Barnett (d. 1972) of West Chester, Pennsylvania for the years 1931-1972 (with the exceptions of 1967 and 1968). Violet Barnett was a homemaker and had two children, Ethel and Earl. Daily entries cover chores, weather, family and social life. There is also the occasional comment on national and international events. Violet Barnett was very engaged in church activities and a member of several chapters of the National Grange. Also included are a few newspapers clippings, invitations, greeting cards, postcards, business cards and miscellaneous notes. A ledger book from 1920 is contained at the end and the identity of the author is not confirmed.
Barnett, Violet L., d. 1972 arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 10/29/2009.
Biographical Note
Married to Joseph Percy Barnett (1882-1967), Violet Laughead Barnett was a homemaker in West Chester, Pa. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Violet L. Barnett.
Scope and Contents
Diaries of Violet Laughead Barnett (d. 1972) of West Chester, Pennsylvania for the years 1931-1972 (with the exceptions of 1967 and 1968). Violet Barnett was a homemaker and had two children, Ethel and Earl. Daily entries cover chores, weather, family and social life. There is also the occasional comment on national and international events. Violet Barnett was very engaged in church activities and a member of several chapters of the National Grange. Also included are a few newspapers clippings, invitations, greeting cards, postcards, business cards and miscellaneous notes. A ledger book from 1920 is contained at the end and the identity of the author is not confirmed.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Grange
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings (information artifacts); Diaries
Geographic Name:
Pennsylvania--Social life and customs--20th century.
Topical Term:
Homemakers--Pennsylvania--Diaries.; Women--Diaries.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- id66672 (Box 1)
  - Diaries, 1931-1932, 1913; id63014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diaries, 1933-1937; id63015 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Diaries, 1938-1942; id63016 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Diaries, 1943-1945; id63019 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diaries, 1946-1950; id63021 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Diaries, 1951-1953; id63022 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Diaries, 1954-1956; id63023 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Diaries, 1957-1959; id63024 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Diaries, 1960-1962; id63025 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Diaries, 1963-1965; id63026 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dairies, 1966 and 1969; id63051 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Diaries, 1970-1972; id63054 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ledger Book, 1920; id63101 (Box 1, Folder 13)